stencyl.com 2015-02-19

# Stencyl - Privacy Policy

For Stencyl.com, StencylForge and the Software.

## The Bottom Line

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Stencyl, we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our services.

If you have questions about accessing or correcting your personal data please [contact us](http://www.stencyl.com/about/contact/).

## Privacy Policy

Stencyl LLC (" **Stencyl** ") owns and operates [Stencyl.com](http://www.stencyl.com/), StencylForge and the Stencyl software itself ("the Software"). It is Stencyl's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites and services.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Stencyl collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Stencyl’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Stencyl’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Stencyl may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Stencyl also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users. Stencyl only discloses logged in user IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of Stencyl where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Stencyl's websites choose to interact with Stencyl in ways that require Stencyl to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Stencyl gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a StencylPass to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Stencyl - by purchasing goods and services from us, for example - are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Stencyl collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with Stencyl. Stencyl does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Stencyl may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites, the use of its services, and the use of content created with its services. For instance, Stencyl may monitor how often the Software is launched in aggregate, how many downloads a resource has received or how many times a game has been launched. Stencyl may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Stencyl does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Stencyl discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Stencyl's behalf or to provide services available at Stencyl's websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Stencyl's websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Stencyl will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Stencyl discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Stencyl believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Stencyl, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Stencyl website and have supplied your email address, Stencyl may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with Stencyl and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Stencyl takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Stencyl uses cookies to help Stencyl identify and track visitors, their usage of Stencyl website, and their website access preferences. Stencyl visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Stencyl's websites, with the drawback that certain features of Stencyl's websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If Stencyl, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Stencyl goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquiror of Stencyl may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Stencyl and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Stencyl may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Stencyl's sole discretion. Stencyl encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

## Revision History

April 4, 2013: Clarified "Aggregated Statistics" section based on a user's feedback.

May 1, 2011: Initial Version based off the [Automattic template](http://automattic.com/privacy/), licensed under Creative Commons.
